# Sam Skaufel

# WFB DEVELOPER

Seattle, WA | Phone: 425-879-5220 | Email: samskaufel@gmail.com | Portfolio: samskaufel.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Web Developer with a strong desire to deliver a seamless experience and intuitive design to the user with clean code. Former healthcare provider who can bring customer-facing experience to making a product that meets the unique needs of the user.

#### SKILLS

- Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript
- Libraries/Frameworks: React, Angular, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node, Express, React Native
- Relational Database: PostgreSQL
- noSQL Databases: MongoDB, Cloud Firestore
- Tools: Postman, Android Studio, Expo
- Cloud: AWS, Heroku

#### **PROJECTS**

### myFlix, Movie Database

- Developed a full-stack web application with MERN
- Built the REST API that interacts with a non-relational database MongoDB
- Implemented basic HTTP authentication and JWT/Token-based authentication/authorization
- Created two responsive, SPA where users can make requests and receive responses from the backend with React and Angular

## Chat, Mobile Messaging Application

- Built using React Native and optimized for both iOS and Android devices
- Developed with Expo/Expo Go and stored chat messages in the Google Firestore database
- Used Gifted Chat to provide users with a chat interface and options to share images and their location

### Meet, Discover Upcoming Local Events

- Built a serverless, PWA with React using a test-driven-development technique
- Implemented data visualization with a charting library Recharts
- Fetched upcoming events using the Google Calendar API

#### Pokédex, Pokémon Database

- Built a small web application with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Used Ajax to send and fetch data asynchronously from an external API Pokémon API
- Implemented a responsive layout with Bootstrap

### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Exercise Physiologist, 2021 – Present

## Alliance Physical Therapy Partners

- Instructed, coached, and educated airplane mechanics in corrective exercise classes which reduced injury rates by 96%
- Marketed our services to increase utilization
- Managed my own schedule and documented every service
- Collaborated with team members to integrate customer feedback into future programming and planning
- Built relationships with clients

# Physical Therapy Aide, 2020 – 2021

## EvergreenHealth

- Communicated with my team what work had been completed and what work still needs to be done
- Effectively communicated errors within the physical therapist's documentation

• Organized and kept equipment/supplies properly stocked to increase workflow and ease of services

**EDUCATION** 

Full-Stack Web Development Certification, 2021 – 2022

CareerFoundry

Bachelor of Science in Nutrition and Exercise Physiology, 2016 – 2020

Washington State University